Badmus Sulaimon Olawole

<u>Haryobamy.badmus@gmail.com, +2348039433746</u> Software Engineer

SUMMARY

Badmus is a skilled, consistent and professional Software Engineer with professional knowledge of maintaining, organizing, implementing and developing information systems and software for human resource, and financial operations. Has experience of customer service in a high-tech environment. Possess a good team spirit, deadline orientated and has the ability to organize and present complex solutions clearly and accurately.

SKILLS

- Version Control (Microsoft - React Js -Database (MySQL, JavaScript Azure, GitHub, Bit Bucket, Firebase, MongoDB) - Node Js AWS) - Selenium - TypeScript - React Native - Angular - HTML State Management (Redux) - RESTful API -CSS-C#

EDUCATION

2018 Higher National Diploma in Electrical Engineering2012 National Diploma in Electrical Engineering

CERTIFICATIONS

2019 ReactJS – Complete guide for frontend developer
2019 The Complete ReactJs Course –Basic to Advance.
2019 National Youth Service Corps (NYSC) Discharge Certificate
2017 Complete Responsive Web Development Course –Basic to Advance

EMPLOYMENT

2021 – till Date Moversly, Australia.
2020- 2021 Sterling Bank, Lagos Nigeria.
2019- 2020 Plus 27 Solutions-, Lagos Nigeria .

LANGUAGES

- English (Full professional proficiency)
- Yoruba (Native Language)

** EXPERIENCE

Front-end Software Engineer • Moversly • Sept. 2021 – till date Responsibilities:

- Developing new user-facing features using React.js and React native for both Mobile and web application
- Building reusable components and front-end libraries for future use

- Translating designs and wireframes into high quality code
- Optimizing components for maximum performance across a vast array of webcapable devices and browsers
- Building pixel-perfect, buttery smooth UIs across both mobile platforms.
- Leveraging native APIs for deep integrations with both platforms.
- Diagnose and fix bugs and performance bottlenecks for performance that feels native.
- Maintain code and write automated tests to ensure the product is of the highest quality.
- Transition existing React web apps to React Native.

Methods and Tools used:

AWS, JavaScript, Node Js, React Js, GitHub, Material UI, React icon, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, NPM, Redux, Swagger Documentation, Postman, Visual Studio Code, Slack, OneDrive, Google Meets, Figma, Jira.

Front-end Software Engineer • Sterling Bank • Dec. 2020 – 2021 Responsibilities:

- Implementing and developing the User interface using Next.js, Ant-Design, bootstrap
- Consuming Restful API for the service call on pages to interact with the server for information
- Translating designs and wireframes into high quality code
- Optimizing components for maximum performance across a vast array of webcapable devices and browsers
- Writing clean, reusable and scalable code use for business logic
- Building pixel-perfect, buttery smooth UIs.
- Diagnose and fix bugs and performance bottlenecks for performance that feels native.
- Maintain code and write automated tests to ensure the product is of the highest quality.

Methods and Tools used:

JavaScript, Next js, TypeScript, Microsoft Azure, Ant-Design, HTML, CSS, redux Swagger Documentation, Visual Studio Code, Figma, Microsoft Teams, .

Front-end Software Engineer • Bonafide • April 2022 Responsibilities:

- Building pixel-perfect, buttery smooth UIs across both mobile platforms.
- Leveraging native APIs for deep integrations with both platforms.
- Diagnose and fix bugs and performance bottlenecks for performance that feels native.
- Reach out to the open source community to encourage and help implement mission-critical software fixes—React Native moves fast and often breaks things.
- Maintaining code and write automated tests to ensure the product is of the highest quality.
- Transition existing React web apps to React Native.

Methods and Tools used:

JavaScript, React Native, Bit Bucket, TypeScript, CSS, Redux, Postman Documentation, Visual Studio Code, Slack, Click Up.

★ COMPETENCE

React Js ***

C# **

Node Js **

Typescript **

Redux **

AWS **

Microsoft Azure ★★★
JavaScript ★★★
RESTful API ★★★
HTML ★★★★
CSS ★★★
GitHub ★★★

MySQL ★★★
MongoDB ★★
Selenium ★★★
React Native ★★★
Angular ★★
Bit Bucket ★★

*
**
**

Some Basic Knowledge Basic Knowledge Good Knowledge Very Good Knowledge Experts